<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020 Christian Beier <info@christianbeier.net> -->
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>net.christianbeier.Gromit-MPX</id>
  
  <name>Gromit-MPX</name>
  <summary>Gromit-MPX is a tool to make annotations on the screen</summary>
  
  <metadata_license>CC-BY-4.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-2.0-only</project_license>

  <content_rating type="oars-1.0">
  </content_rating>

  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/bk138/gromit-mpx</url>

  <developer_name>Christian Beier</developer_name>

  <recommends>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </recommends>
  
  <description>
    <p>
      Gromit-MPX is an on-screen annotation tool that works with any Unix desktop environment under X11 as well as Wayland.
    </p>
    <p>
      Its main use is for making presentations of some application. Normally, you would have to move the mouse pointer around the point of interest until hopefully everybody noticed it. With Gromit-MPX, you can draw everywhere onto the screen, highlighting some button or area.
    </p>
    <p>Key features include:</p>
    <ul>
    <li><em>Desktop-independent.</em> Gromit-MPX works with GNOME, KDE, XFCE, ... under X11 as well as with a Wayland session</li>
    <li><em>Hotkey-based.</em>Does not get into your way of doing things by sticking some UI widget on your desktop</li>
    <li><em>Configurable.</em>You are free to change key bindings as well as drawing tool configuration</li>
    <li><em>Multi-Pointer.</em>Under X11, it enables graphical annotations with several pointers at once</li>
    <li><em>Fast.</em>Where available, Gromit-MPX makes use of Compositing</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  
  <launchable type="desktop-id">net.christianbeier.Gromit-MPX.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bk138/gromit-mpx/master/data/on-gnome-wayland.png</image>
      <caption>Gromit-MPX running on GNOME under Wayland</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bk138/gromit-mpx/master/data/on-kde.png</image>
      <caption>Gromit-MPX running on KDE</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/bk138/gromit-mpx/master/data/on-xfce4.png</image>
      <caption>Gromit-MPX running on XFCE</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>

  <releases>
    <release version="1.4.2" date="2022-02-12">
      <description>
	<p>
	  Fixed Gromit-MPX blocking mouse clicks to other apps on Wayland in certain conditions.
	  Also fixed toggling from GNOME systray with gnome-shell-extension-appindicator under X11.
	</p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.4.1" date="2022-02-03">
      <description>
	<p>
	  Fixed hotkey setting from config file for XFCE, the erase tool is now working properly
	  when not using a composited display and the Flatpak now displays the tray icon correctly
	  on more platforms. Also fixed some Flatpak hotkey issues.
	</p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.4" date="2020-12-03">
      <description>
	<p>
	  Gromit-MPX 1.4 now runs on Wayland, displays activation status in the tray menu,
	  added Flatpak packaging and fixed activation via tray menu on KDE.
	</p>
      </description>
    </release>

    <release version="1.3.1" date="2020-08-01">
      <description>
	<p>
	  Documented donation options, added ability to configure the hot key and undo key in
	  gromit-mpx.cfg and added GUI error displays in case one of the hotkeys can't be grabbed.
	</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
